[music]
[Instructor] Now we can control
the enemies spawning
whenever they all leave the scene.
So what we're going to do is
increase the number of enemies
every time we defeat a wave.
So, we'll have 1 spawn, and then we can
have 2 spawn, and 3, and so on.
In our SpawnManager Script
we're going to use
a variable to control...
the actual number
of enemies in the wave.
So, we'll make a public variable
so we can see what it does again,
make it an Integer,
and then we'll call it "waveNumber,"
and we'll set it to 1
in the beginning,
and then we'll actually use
this waveNumber to dictate
how many enemies should spawn
after we defeat every enemy.
In our "if() statement,"
since this is where we know
when enemies are defeated,
this is actually where we'll "increment"
our waveNumber.
So we'll change
our "SpawnEnemyWave(),"
and start to be wave number,
so this will spawn 1
enemy at the beginning.
Now, when we've defeated
all of the enemies
we'll set waveNumber,
and we'll use
that "++," this time.
So now when the enemies
are all defeated,
it will increase waveNumber by 1,
so now waveNumber should be 2.
And then if we change the enemies
to Spawn Parameter,
to be a wave number here,
so then it should spawn
2 enemies afterwards.
So, now if we test
our game,
we should see 1 enemy spawn;
there we go.
And then if we hit
this enemy off,
2 enemies spawn.
Then see if we can hit both.
Oh, we have 1.
And the last 1
will go off,
and then do we get 3?
And there you go.
So, now in your SpawnManager Script,
you're going to add
another variable
to keep track of the waveNumber.
So we'll set it to 1,
and we'll make it public
so we can see what it's doing.
In our Start() Method,
change EnemyWave to waveNumber,
and then in our Update() Method,
where we can actually keep track
of when we hit the point
where all the enemies
are off the scene,
and we create a new one,
we'll increment wave number
by 1 here,
and then we'll spawn
a new EnemyWave using
the incremented number.
Now it's your turn.
[music]